University Of Connecticut
© 2005 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [George A. Works, 1929-1930].
undated, 1926-1930.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut.
.75 linear feet.
George Alan Works assumed the presidency of Connecticut Agricultural College in 1929 after a distinguished career at the University of Chicago.
MSS19980178
Biography
George Alan Works assumed the presidency of Connecticut Agricultural College in 1929 after a distinguished career at the University of Chicago. In his inaugural speech, President Works called for the improvement of the college's programs in liberal arts and the natural sciences, as well as in agriculture and mechanic arts. When the obstacles to his ambitious plans for the development of the college appeared to be too formidable, Works resigned his position after one year in order to accept another position at Chicago. The most important achievement of his administration was the accreditation of the college in 1930.
Scope and Content
The records consist of the general correspondence of the President of the College. It is the only extant collection of the papers of the president for this period. The correspondence is concerned with internal administrative matters, major policy issues at the college, with the college's relations with state and federal governments, and with other educational agencies and institutions.
Arrangement
In 2001, the (early) Presidential records were reprocessed and separated by presidential tenure.
Series I: Correspondence ( undated, 1926-1930 ) documents the activities and concerns of the President during his brief administration. Of particular note are the files pertaining to the events surrounding the inauguration of George Works.
Series II: Photographs ( undated ) includes several photographs removed from Series I.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Works, George A. (George Alan), 1877-1957.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut. Office of the President.; University of Connecticut—Presidents.; University of Connecticut—History.; College presidents—Connecticut.; Universities and colleges—Administration.; Universities and colleges—Accreditation.; University of Connecticut--Faculty--Personal and professional papers.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Blueprints.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Press release.; Photocopies.; Notes.
Occupations:
Administrator.; Librarian.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The records of the President's Office from 1908 to 1935 were stored in Gulley Hall until about 1960, when they were relocated to the attic of Beach Hall.
Acquisition Information
In 1968, the records were brought to the Special Collections Department. They were then transferred to Historical Manuscripts and Archives in August 1979 and were arranged and described in the spring of 1980. In 1995, Special Collections and Historical Manuscripts and Archives merged to form Archives & Special Collections and were relocated to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Return to University of Connecticut, President's Office Records.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1926-1930
  - Accounting system of college, 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Accrediting of C.A.C., undated, 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Applications—Mathematics, 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Buckingham, S. McLean—Commissioner of Ag., 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Buckley, John (Trustee), 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - C, 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Capen, E.W., 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Carillon—General, 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Carillon—Meneely and Company, 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Chimes—J.C. Deagan, Inc., 1929-1930 (Box OS, 1:, Folder 10)
  - Chimes—McShane Bell Foundry, Co., 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Chimes—John Taylor and Co., 1926, 1930 (Box OS, 1:, Folder 12)
  - Committee of Deans, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut Bankers Association, 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Eaton, Edwin C. (Boston Alumni Assoc. of C.A.C.), undated, 1928-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Ellis, B.W. [Director of Extension Service], 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Grange, undated, 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Greene, Arthur F. (Trustee), 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Gumbart, Edward H. (Economics), 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Hall, Edward F.—Commissioner of Finance and Control, 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Hendrickson, C.I. (Agricultural Economics), 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - Hollister, S.P., undated, 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - Hough, Clifford E. (Trustee), 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Housing Committee, 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Inauguration of President Works
    - Banquet Speeches, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - Committee working papers, 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1929-1930 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
      - Outgoing, 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - Form letters, 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - Letters of Acceptance, 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - Letters of Regret, 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - Program, 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - Response cards, 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
  - Land Grant Colleges, undated, 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 35)
  - Leroy, Harwood P. (Trustee), 1929-1930 (Box 2:, Folder 36)
  - Lowrie, Charles N.—Landscape Architect, 1930 (Box 2:, Folder 37)
  - M, undated, 1929-1930 (Box 2:, Folder 38)
  - Manchester, H.G. (Trustee), 1929-1930 (Box 2:, Folder 39)
  - N, undated (Box 3:, Folder 40)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1929-1930 (Box 3:, Folder 41)
  - P, undated, 1930 (Box 3:, Folder 42)
  - Perry, Delbert K.—Architect, 1930 (Box 3:, Folder 43)
  - Registrar, undated, 1929-1930 (Box 3:, Folder 44)
  - Retirement, undated (Box 3:, Folder 45)
  - Slate, W.L. (Experiment Station), undated, 1929 (Box 3:, Folder 46)
  - T, 1930 (Box 3:, Folder 47)
  - Tax Commissioner, 1929 (Box 3:, Folder 48)
  - Women's Student Government Association, 1930 (Box 3:, Folder 49)
- Series II: Photographs, undated
  - Photographs, undated (Box 3:, Folder 50)
  - Return to University of Connecticut, President's Office Records.